{
    "id": "3f79a5642db242b38c9d2054f3cb4f6c",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The man complained that he ………………………….",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, we need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is robbed",
                "has been robbed",
                "had been robbed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9b1f3596246040178c5d298ac91f3dfd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She asked me if she ………………………….. use my laptop.",
            "description": "Could is the past tense of can. When the main verb is in the past tense, we need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6c3ed0026a18450a82ac96f6d792d759"
        },
        {
            "question": "I want to know why you ………………………. to me.",
            "description": "Use do with you. In the simple present tense, we make questions and negatives with do and does.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't talk",
                "don't talk",
                "not talk"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "184a4991ad5245a7a83f9303a3fd5156"
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for hours but she …………………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't turned up",
                "doesn't turn up",
                "didn't turn up"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "cbbf509ce5374048a1ad0a829664dd16"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. a little faster, you could overtake her.",
            "description": "In type 2 conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could / might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "run",
                "ran",
                "have run",
                "had run"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "147a50ad9ee5466ab3ce015849ff4d82"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you …………………………… blaming others for your failures.",
            "description": "After it is time, a past tense is used with a present or future meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "have stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "63affafee85748f3a4bd0a66896a17a2"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish I ……………………………. fly.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "220070d61d374f0ca2106ea357e0b84f"
        },
        {
            "question": "What will you do if you …………………………….. that job?",
            "description": "In type 1 conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will / can / may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "don't get",
                "didn't get",
                "hadn't got"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "90414c9f74b24389ba241f2656335162"
        },
        {
            "question": "By next September, I …………………………… in this college for twenty years.",
            "description": "We use the future perfect to say that an activity will have completed by a certain point of time in future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will teach",
                "would teach",
                "will have taught"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "798b93f4353d452baa9b23e259710f12"
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her what she …………………………. there.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is doing",
                "was doing",
                "has been doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cd30b65e65a14c08984a4c2bacbf4019"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. the job by next Monday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will finish",
                "will be finishing",
                "will have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6d20fcac916e42c4ba31e0dad7616a78"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………….. ill for two months, before he died.",
            "description": "Perfect tenses are more common with the time expressions for and since. We use the past perfect to talk about the earlier of two past events. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "afdaff9a13f54245b9c62f9393aa6e8e"
        }
    ]
}